# Pablo Román Clares

Amsterdam, the Netherlands

pablo.roman85@gmail.com



+31 612551483



linkedin.com/in/pabloroman85



https://pabloroman.es

# Summary

I'm a software engineer based in Amsterdam with over 15 years of experience building technical teams and digital products.

Throughout my career I've worked in management and individual contributor roles and I have a broad vision about software engineering: I am extremely customer-focused, and I care more about user experience and business impact than about any particular technology or tool to solve the problem.

I'm open to fully remote jobs only.

# **Experience**

## CTO

Squares

Apr 2022 - Present (1 year 6 months)

Squares is a company that offers event organisers an affordable solution to produce their own branded digital event experiences.

- \* Led the design, implementation, and architecture of key product areas including analytics, gamification, content builders, admin panels, and authorization/authentication.
- \* Mentored and trained a team of 10 developers in Agile software development methodologies, design patterns (e.g., event sourcing and SOLID principles), and automated testing for improved code maintainability and platform stability.
- \* Successfully managed and coordinated remote work environment with seamless communication and collaboration, ensuring efficient workflow and productivity.

### **Engineering Manager**

Mollie

Nov 2019 - Apr 2022 (2 years 6 months)

Mollie is a fast-growing fintech company based in The Netherlands that makes payments simple for over 130K+ merchants across Europe.

- \* Led and managed two teams of 6-8 engineers, overseeing multiple projects within the analytics section of the merchant dashboard.
- \* Successfully rebuilt the backend for the analytics section, resulting in a significant performance improvement.
- \* Implemented enhanced monitoring and alerting systems for third-party payment providers, ensuring seamless operations and minimizing downtime.
- \* Made impactful contributions to hiring, recruiting, and career progression processes for a diverse engineering team of over 100 professionals.

# CTO

#### TNW

Oct 2015 - Nov 2019 (4 years 2 months)

TNW is an international technology media and events company. TNW organises TNW Conference, a technology festival with now 17.500 attendees and publishes an influential tech news site with over 10M visitors a month.

- \* Led the engineering of two new successful products that were key assets during the company's acquisition by the Financial Times:
- An event management and ticketing software used by the TNW Conference team to drive ticket sales and design the attendee experience
- A business-intelligence software that tracked activity of listed and private tech companies worldwide



## سس Full Stack Engineer

#### **TNW**

Mar 2010 - Oct 2015 (5 years 8 months)

- \* Contributed to the development and maintenance of several key products of TNW:
- The news site thenextweb.com, with an audience of over 10M visitors a month
- The social media analytics service twittercounter.com, one of the largest consumers of the Twitter API at the time



### **Full Stack Engineer**

#### Move

Feb 2008 - Mar 2010 (2 years 2 months)

In my first job as a developer, I acquired foundational knowledge about APIs, databases, backend development in PHP, web development (HTML/CSS/JS), server administration, infrastructure and mobile app development.

#### **Education**



#### Universidad de Almería

MSc, Computer Science 2003 - 2008